Hugh Clark Papers
© 2006 University of Connecticut
Hugh Clark Papers.
undated, 1947-1998.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Clark, Hugh, 1914-
34 linear feet.
Hugh Clark received his bachelor's degree from Clark University in 1934 and a doctoral degree from the University of Michigan in 1941. He was employed by the University of Iowa from 1945 to 1947, when he joined the faculty at the University of Connecticut. Clark specialized in developmental biology and retired from the University in 1983. The collection contains correspondence, administrative, professional and personnel files relating to Clark's responsibilities and interests.
MSS19950016
Biography
Born on 15 April 1914 in Pawling, New York, Hugh Clark received his bachelor's degree from Clark University in 1934 and a doctoral degree from the University of Michigan in 1941.
Clark was professor of physiology at the College of Osteopathy in Des Moines, Iowa, from 1941 until 1945. In 1945, he became an assistant professor of zoology at the University of Iowa. Dr. Clark joined the faculty at the University of Connecticut in 1947. He was made a full professor in 1959.
During his career at the University of Connecticut, Clark was involved in a variety of academic endeavors. In 1960, he was named Director of the Institute of Cellular Biology. He directed the Research Foundation from its establishment in 1963 until 1983. In addition, he acted as Associate Dean of the Graduate School from 1963-1982, as Interim Dean from 1977-1979, and became Associate Vice-president from 1982. He held this last position until his retirement on 31 December 1983.
Clark specialized in developmental biology with a research interest in nitrogen excretion and metabolism.
An active member of the profession, Clark earned numerous distinctions and honors. He served on the governor's Committee on Environmental Policy in 1970, the Connecticut Research Commission from 1965-1971, and the Governor's Advisory Committee on Mental Retardation from 1966-1967. He received the Alumni Association Award for Leadership Excellence from the University of Connecticut in 1976. He was also a member of many professional societies including the American Society of Zoologists, the New York Academy of Science, the Society for Developmental Biology, the American Association for the Advancement of Science, and the American Association of University Professors.
Hugh Clark died 24 August 2005 at the age of 91.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, administrative, professional and personnel files relating to Clark's responsibilities and interests. The collection also contains student records and written doctoral examinations. This latter portion of the collection is restricted. Additions to the collection include personal and professional papers, research materials for publications and correspondence.
Arrangement
Series I: Correspondence ( undated, 1961-1962 )
Series II: Experiment Notes ( undated, 1948-1961 )
Series III: American Association of University Professors ( undated, 1948-1952 )
Series IV: Student Files ( undated )
Series V: Box Inventory of later Additions ( undated, 1947-1998 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Bountiful Land Dodd A5688
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Clark, Hugh, 1914-
Organizations:
University of Connecticut--Graduate School.; University of Connecticut--Biological Sciences Group.; University of Connecticut--Institute of Cellular Biology.; University of Connecticut--Faculty--Personal and professional papers.; University of Connecticut--Students.; American Association of University Professors--University of Connecticut Chapter.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)--Science and scientific affairs--Research institutes.; Connecticut--Societies, etc.--Education.; Connecticut--Science and scientific affairs--Research institutes.; Storrs (Conn.)--Societies, etc.--Education.; Connecticut--Education--Universities and colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.
Subjects:
Biology--Study and teaching--Connecticut.; Cytology.; Embryology--Research--Connecticut.; College teachers--Connecticut.; College teachers--Societies.; Universities and colleges--Connecticut.; Research institutes--Connecticut.; Education--Connecticut.; Education--Societies, etc.; Biology--Research--Connecticut.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Notebooks.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Minutes.; Diaries.; School Records.; Manuscripts.; Photocopies.; Notes.; Newsletters.; Newspapers.
Occupations:
Biologists--Connecticut.; College teachers--Connecticut.; Biology teachers--Connecticut.; Departmental chairmen (Universities)--Connecticut.; Deans (Education)--Connecticut.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection with the exception of Series IV: Student Records.
Acquisition Information
The materials in the collection were donated by Dr. Clark, or his family, beginning in 1995 and continuing through 2006.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1961-1962
  - Afzelius, Bjorn, undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - American Heart Association, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Argow, W.W., undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Average drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Babbidge, Homer D., undated (Box 1:, Folder 5-6)
  - Barr, Charles E., undated (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Beck, Sidney, undated (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Bernstein, Emil, undated (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Beyer, Robert, undated (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Bieber, Allen, undated (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Biophysics, undated (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Bowles, Charles, undated (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Briles, Connally O., undated (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Brown, William Paul, undated (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Cagle, Fred, undated (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Calabi, Ornella, undated (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Carter, Dean W. Harrison, undated (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Chapman, George, undated (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Chase, Herman, undated (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Cloney, Richard A., undated (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - Collins, Ralph, undated (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - Communications Department, undated (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - Computer, undated (Box 1:, Folder 24)
  - Conley, Joseph J., Jr., undated (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - Delamater, Edward D., undated (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - Deluca, Chester or Hotchkiss, undated (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - Demerec, Milislav, undated (Box 1:, Folder 28)
  - Dorr, J.V.H., undated (Box 1:, Folder 29)
  - "Dynamics of Development", undated (Box 1:, Folder 30)
  - Division of Biological Sciences, undated (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - Electron microscopy, undated (Box 1:, Folder 32)
  - Elsevier Publishing Company, undated (Box 1:, Folder 33)
  - Embryology Seminar, 1961-1962 (Box 1:, Folder 34)
  - Eppenberger, Hans M., undated (Box 1:, Folder 35)
  - Frankhauser, G., undated (Box 1:, Folder 36)
  - Ferm, Vergil, undated (Box 1:, Folder 37)
  - Fingles, F.O., undated (Box 1:, Folder 38)
  - Fox, Allen, undated (Box 1:, Folder 39)
  - Friedman, Don, undated (Box 1:, Folder 40)
  - Funk, Casimir, undated (Box 1:, Folder 41)
  - Gamma Irradiator, undated (Box 1:, Folder 42)
  - Gibbons, I.R., undated (Box 1:, Folder 43)
  - Greenawalt, J.W., undated (Box 1:, Folder 44)
  - Guild, Walter, undated (Box 1:, Folder 45)
  - Hack, M.H., undated (Box 1:, Folder 46)
  - Halloran, T.J., undated (Box 1:, Folder 47)
  - Hamilton, Howard L., undated (Box 1:, Folder 48)
  - Hansborough, Lewis, undated (Box 1:, Folder 49)
  - Hass, Hermann, undated (Box 1:, Folder 50)
  - Hoagland, Mahlon B., undated (Box 1:, Folder 51)
  - Hotel rates, undated (Box 1:, Folder 52)
  - Hsu, T.C., undated (Box 1:, Folder 53)
  - Industrial Electronic Products-RCA, undated (Box 1:, Folder 54)
  - Inge, F.D., undated (Box 1:, Folder 55)
  - Institute Policies, undated (Box 1:, Folder 56)
  - Jaffee, Julian J., undated (Box 1:, Folder 57)
  - Jenerick, undated (Box 1:, Folder 58)
  - Jorgensen, A.N., undated (Box 1:, Folder 59-60)
  - Kaye, Gordon, undated (Box 1:, Folder 61)
  - Kaye, Gordon, undated (Box 1:, Folder 62)
  - Heim, Karrer, undated (Box 1:, Folder 63)
  - Kessel, Richard, undated (Box 1:, Folder 64)
  - Keys, undated (Box 1:, Folder 65)
  - Kidney function proposal, undated (Box 1:, Folder 66)
  - Klein, Norman W., undated (Box 1:, Folder 67)
  - Knauss, Harold P., undated (Box 1:, Folder 68)
  - Koritz, S.B., undated (Box 1:, Folder 69)
  - Lalor Foundation, undated (Box 2:, Folder 70)
  - Langer, Bernhardt W., Jr., undated (Box 2:, Folder 71)
  - Lederle Labs, undated (Box 2:, Folder 72)
  - Lepper, Robert J., undated (Box 2:, Folder 73)
  - Leventhal, David E., undated (Box 2:, Folder 74)
  - Liberman, undated (Box 2:, Folder 75)
  - Lucas, Joseph J., undated (Box 2:, Folder 76)
  - Mansfield Lions Club, undated (Box 2:, Folder 77)
  - Marshak, Alfred, undated (Box 2:, Folder 78)
  - Masoro, Edward J., undated (Box 2:, Folder 79)
  - Mayo, Leonard W., undated (Box 2:, Folder 80)
  - McCauley, Robert, undated (Box 2:, Folder 81-82)
  - Meador, R.G., undated (Box 2:, Folder 83)
  - Mercer, E.H., undated (Box 2:, Folder 84)
  - Miller, Alexander, undated (Box 2:, Folder 85)
  - Mintz, Beatrice, undated (Box 2:, Folder 86)
  - Minutes of meetings-Graduate School, undated (Box 2:, Folder 87)
  - Morgan, Richard, undated (Box 2:, Folder 88)
  - Morowitz, Harold J., undated (Box 2:, Folder 89)
  - Moses, Montrose, undated (Box 2:, Folder 90)
  - Mundkur, Balaji, undated (Box 2:, Folder 91)
  - Muscular Dystrophy, undated (Box 2:, Folder 92)
  - Nakai, J., undated (Box 2:, Folder 93)
  - Napolitano, Leonard, undated (Box 2:, Folder 94)
  - Newcomer, Earl H., undated (Box 2:, Folder 95)
  - N.I.H. A-834, undated (Box 2:, Folder 96-97)
  - N.I.H. A-834, undated (Box 2:, Folder 98)
  - Northrop, Robert Burr, undated (Box 2:, Folder 99)
  - Odor, Louise, undated (Box 2:, Folder 100)
  - Office of Provost, undated (Box 2:, Folder 101)
  - Page-Carlson Wing, undated (Box 2:, Folder 102)
  - Palade, George, undated (Box 2:, Folder 103)
  - Palay, Sanford, undated (Box 2:, Folder 104)
  - Papaconstantinou, John, undated (Box 2:, Folder 105)
  - Pappas, George, undated (Box 2:, Folder 106)
  - Philip Grant (NSF Develop Biology), undated (Box 2:, Folder 107)
  - Phillips Committee, undated (Box 2:, Folder 108)
  - Photographers, undated (Box 2:, Folder 109)
  - Pickett, B.W., undated (Box 2:, Folder 110)
  - Plough, H.H., undated (Box 2:, Folder 111)
  - Pomerat, C.M., undated (Box 2:, Folder 112)
  - Porter, undated (Box 2:, Folder 113)
  - Preiss, John W., undated (Box 2:, Folder 114)
  - President's Newsletter, undated (Box 2:, Folder 115)
  - Prosser, C.L., undated (Box 2:, Folder 116)
  - Public Health Service, undated (Box 2:, Folder 117)
  - Reger, James, undated (Box 2:, Folder 118)
  - Reprint requests, undated (Box 2:, Folder 119)
  - Research Foundation-RNA, undated (Box 2:, Folder 120)
  - Requests, undated (Box 2:, Folder 121)
  - Reynolds, Orland B., undated (Box 2:, Folder 122)
  - Richardson, Dorothy, undated (Box 2:, Folder 123)
  - Roth, Jay S., undated (Box 2:, Folder 124)
  - Runner, Meredith, undated (Box 2:, Folder 125)
  - Savage, Alice M., undated (Box 3:, Folder 126)
  - Schairer, Ernest, undated (Box 3:, Folder 127)
  - Schick, Dean, undated (Box 3:, Folder 128)
  - Scholastic Student Committee Report, undated (Box 3:, Folder 129)
  - Schwinck, Isle, undated (Box 3:, Folder 130)
  - Sloan, Alfred P. Foundation, undated (Box 3:, Folder 131)
  - Small, Theodore, undated (Box 3:, Folder 132)
  - Smith, David, undated (Box 3:, Folder 133)
  - Society for the Study of Development and Growth, undated (Box 3:, Folder 134)
  - Special professorships, undated (Box 3:, Folder 135)
  - Seift, Henson, undated (Box 3:, Folder 136)
  - Threshold, undated (Box 3:, Folder 137)
  - Tobin, Michael, undated (Box 3:, Folder 138)
  - Twentieth Anniversary Convocation, undated (Box 3:, Folder 139)
  - Twombly, Shelia, undated (Box 3:, Folder 140)
  - Van Breemer, undated (Box 3:, Folder 141)
  - Vegotsky, Allen, undated (Box 3:, Folder 142)
  - Volpe, E. Peter, undated (Box 3:, Folder 143)
  - Wachtel, Allen, undated (Box 3:, Folder 144)
  - Waelsch, Salome G., undated (Box 3:, Folder 145)
  - Waugh, Albert E., undated (Box 3:, Folder 146)
  - Weber, Rudolf, undated (Box 3:, Folder 147)
  - Wedberg, Stanley E., undated (Box 3:, Folder 148)
  - Wetherell, Donald, undated (Box 3:, Folder 149)
  - Medical recommendations, undated (Box 3:, Folder 150-151)
  - Wharton, Charles H., undated (Box 3:, Folder 152)
  - Wilczyski, Jan Z., undated (Box 3:, Folder 153)
  - Wills, Irvin A., undated (Box 3:, Folder 154)
  - Wilson, J. Walter, undated (Box 3:, Folder 155)
  - Wolfson, Nancy, undated (Box 3:, Folder 156)
  - Yesair, David W., undated (Box 3:, Folder 157)
  - Zobel, C. Richard, undated (Box 3:, Folder 158)
  - Zoology Department, undated (Box 3:, Folder 159)
  - Zwilling, Edgar, undated (Box 3:, Folder 160)
- Series II: Experiment Notes, undated, 1948-1961
  - Biology class, undated (Box 3:, Folder 161)
  - Chapter on excretion, undated (Box 3:, Folder 162)
  - Data, undated (Box 3:, Folder 163)
  - Elophe eggs 6,7, undated (Box 3:, Folder 164)
  - Embryology research, undated (Box 3:, Folder 165-168)
  - G-11, undated (Box 3:, Folder 169)
  - G-12, undated (Box 3:, Folder 170)
  - G-13, undated (Box 3:, Folder 171)
  - G-14, undated (Box 4:, Folder 172)
  - G-15, undated (Box 4:, Folder 173)
  - G-16, undated (Box 4:, Folder 174)
  - G-17, undated (Box 4:, Folder 175)
  - G-18, undated (Box 4:, Folder 176)
  - G-19, undated (Box 4:, Folder 177)
  - G-20, undated (Box 4:, Folder 178)
  - G-22, undated (Box 4:, Folder 179)
  - Graphs, undated (Box 4:, Folder 180)
  - Metabolism of the black snake embryo, undated (Box 4:, Folder 181)
  - NIH--Division of Gneral Medical Science, undated (Box 4:, Folder 182)
  - NIH--Kidney, 1960 (Box 4:, Folder 183)
  - NIH--RG-3827, undated (Box 4:, Folder 184)
  - NSF application for foreign travel, undated (Box 4:, Folder 185)
  - NSF, 1955 (Box 4:, Folder 186)
  - Orthinine calibration, undated (Box 4:, Folder 187)
  - Phosphotase--Galleria, 1948 (Box 4:, Folder 188)
  - Research publication, undated (Box 4:, Folder 189)
  - Thesis, undated (Box 4:, Folder 190)
  - Turtle data, undated (Box 4:, Folder 191)
  - Xanthine oxidase, undated (Box 4:, Folder 192-195)
- Series III: American Association of University Professors, undated, 1948-1952
  - Articles, undated (Box 5:, Folder 196)
  - Bulletins, undated (Box 5:, Folder 197-198)
  - First Purchasing committee, undated (Box 5:, Folder 199)
  - Iowa chapter, undated (Box 5:, Folder 200)
  - Letter to Governor, undated (Box 5:, Folder 201)
  - Meeting agendas, undated (Box 5:, Folder 202)
  - Meeting notes, undated (Box 5:, Folder 203-204)
  - Membership, 1951-1952 (Box 5:, Folder 205-206)
  - Milieu, undated (Box 5:, Folder 207)
  - News bulletin, undated (Box 5:, Folder 208)
  - Officers, undated (Box 5:, Folder 209)
  - Other chapters, undated (Box 5:, Folder 210)
  - Proposed revision of the constitution of the Chapter, undated (Box 5:, Folder 211)
  - Reports, undated (Box 5:, Folder 212)
  - Resolutions adopted, 1948-1951 (Box 5:, Folder 213)
  - Second purchasing report, undated (Box 5:, Folder 214)
- Series IV: Student Files, undated
- Series V: Box Inventory of later Additions, undated, 1947-1998
  - Iowa Correspondence, L - Q, undated (Box 7)
  - Iowa Correspondence, R - Z, undated (Box 7)
  - Correspondence/Recommendations, undated (Box 7)
  - Academic Bills, Financial and personal information, undated (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, manuscripts, legal records, ephemera, undated (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, B - Z, undated (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, graduate school, undated (Box 9)
  - Mrs. Dale--Railroad, undated (Box 9)
  - Dale Institute, undated (Box 9)
  - Southeast Connecticut Community needs, undated (Box 9)
  - Nutritional Sciences, undated (Box 9)
  - Articles, undated (Box 9)
  - Program Review Committee, undated (Box 9)
  - School of Allied Health, undated (Box 9)
  - Biotechnology Institute/McFadden, undated (Box 9)
  - Day of Pride, undated (Box 9)
  - Minorities, undated (Box 9)
  - Summary00Haldane Comparison, undated (Box 10)
  - Thermobarameter Check, undated (Box 10)
  - E-2, undated (Box 10)
  - Elophe Eggs--General, undated (Box 10)
  - Neonatal, undated (Box 10)
  - E-1, undated (Box 10)
  - Manuscript on "Observations on the Metabolism of Adult, Neonatal and Embryonic Snakes,", undated (Box 10)
  - Graphs, charts and data, undated (Box 10)
  - Manuscripts and data, undated (Box 10)
  - Chick Respiration, undated (Box 10)
  - Data, undated (Box 10)
  - Calculations--Nitrogen Excretion, 1952 (Box 10)
  - Physical Goal, undated (Box 10)
  - Heterodon Notes, undated (Box 10)
  - Acid Analysis, undated (Box 10)
  - Amonia Production, undated (Box 10)
  - Elophe Egg 2, undated (Box 10)
  - Elophe Egg 8, undated (Box 10)
  - Eggs grouped, undated (Box 10)
  - G-3, undated (Box 10)
  - Elophe Eggs 1, undated (Box 10)
  - G-0, undated (Box 10)
  - G-00, undated (Box 10)
  - G-4, undated (Box 10)
  - Elophe Eggs 3, 4, undated (Box 10)
  - G-5, undated (Box 10)
  - Sabbatical correspondence, undated (Box 10)
  - Notes, undated (Box 10)
  - Alligator manuscript and data, undated (Box 10)
  - Developmental Biology, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Examinations--Biology 219, 1973-1981 (Box 10)
  - Guest Lecture notes, undated (Box 10)
  - Lecture Notes, undated (Box 10)
  - Publications, undated (Box 10)
  - Progress report for grant, undated (Box 10)
  - Iowa Correspondence, A - C, undated (Box 10)
  - Crotophytos Eggs, undated (Box 11)
  - Crotophytos, undated (Box 11)
  - Academic Science report--Earthworm, undated (Box 11)
  - Review Sheets and correspondence, undated (Box 11)
  - Homogamy--Humans/Earthworms, undated (Box 11)
  - Doctoral thesis, 1941 (Box 11)
  - "Physiology of the Fetus,", undated (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 11)
  - Notes, undated (Box 11)
  - Zoology notes, undated (Box 11)
  - Developmental physiology, undated (Box 11)
  - Research references, undated (Box 11)
  - Notes--Biology 201, 1933 (Box 11)
  - Dynamics of development paper, undated (Box 11)
  - Zoology paper, undated (Box 11)
  - Zoology 331 lab, undated (Box 11)
  - Synopses of courses, undated (Box 11)
  - Neurology outline, undated (Box 11)
  - Comparative physiology, undated (Box 11)
  - Physiology, undated (Box 11)
  - Reflexes--Respiration, undated (Box 11)
  - G-1, undated (Box 11)
  - E-3, undated (Box 11)
  - Research drafts, undated (Box 11)
  - Iowa Correspondence, D - J, undated (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1952-1956 (Box 12)
    - A - Z
    - Personal
  - Graduate students, 1959-1962 (Box 12)
  - I. MacKellar, School of Home Economics, undated (Box 12)
  - Department of the Army, undated (Box 12)
  - Scholarships, undated (Box 12)
  - Scholars, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
  - Minorities, undated (Box 12)
  - Threshold, undated (Box 13)
  - University publications, undated (Box 13)
  - Fund for Excellence--Proposal for Biotechnology Center, undated (Box 13)
  - Cooperative High Tech Grants, undated (Box 13)
  - Fund for Excellence proposals and Cooperative high Technology Research and development grant program, undated (Box 13)
  - Master Plan for Higher Education in Connecticut, 1974-1979, undated (Box 13)
  - Technology Center papers, undated (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 13)
  - Connecticut Technology Institute, undated (Box 13)
  - CASE Reports, 1987 (Box 13)
  - Articles and papers, undated (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 14)
  - Reptile bibliography, undated (Box 14)
  - Personal papers, undated (Box 14)
  - Administrative records, undated (Box 14)
  - UConn Mission statements, 1976 (Box 14)
  - AES/CES Research Report, 1989 July (Box 14)
  - Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, undated (Box 14)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 14)
  - UCEPI, undated (Box 14)
  - Connecticut Academy of Science and Engineering, undated (Box 14)
  - Connecticut Academy of Science and Engineering Reports, undated (Box 14)
  - Circulatory, Heart, Blood, undated (Box 14)
  - US National Plant Germplasm system, undated (Box 14)
  - Opportunities for the 1980s, undated (Box 14)
  - Long Range Plan for the School of Engineering (UConn), undated (Box 14)
  - UConn 2000 Report, undated (Box 14)
  - "Advances in the use of biological monitoring techniques to detect toxic pollutants,", undated (Box 14)
  - Photograph (rolled), undated (Box 14)
  - "Designing the Future,", 1989 (Box 15)
  - Notes, undated (Box 15)
  - Agriculture Biotechnology, undated (Box 15)
  - Notes on Walter Landauer, undated (Box 15)
  - Lectures and notes, undated (Box 15)
  - Botany, Embryology, Cytology, Parasitology, Biology notes and papers, undated (Box 15)
  - Slides, undated (Box 16)
  - Diagrams and drawings, undated (Box 16)
  - Articles and papers, undated (Box 16)
  - Research on Walter Landauer, undated (Box 17)
  - National Center for Manufacturing Sciences in Connecticut, undated (Box 18)
  - Institute for Environmental Health, undated (Box 18)
  - Papers, data, notes and articles, undated (Box 18)
  - Connecticut Academy of Science and Engineering reports and minutes, undated (Box 18)
  - Personal papers, undated (Box 18)
  - National Science Board, undated (Box 18)
  - School of Allied Health Strategic Plan, undated (Box 18)
  - AAUP/Landuer research, undated (Box 18)
  - Hugh Clark Lectureship, undated (Box 18)
  - Institute for Environmental Health, undated (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 19)
  - New Rural Society Project, 1972-1973 (Box 19)
  - Environmental Science Information Center, undated (Box 19)
  - Reprints, undated (Box 19)
  - Connecticut Academy of Science and Engineering, undated (Box 19)
  - Molecular and Cell Biology, undated (Box 19)
  - Landauer research, undated (Box 19)
  - Retirement, undated (Box 19)
  - Proposal--coexistence at the turn of the millenium, undated (Box 19)
  - Notes, undated (Box 20)
  - Entolmology, undated (Box 20)
  - Personal papers, undated (Box 20)
  - Physiology Lab, undated (Box 20)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 21)
  - Chapters 1 and 2, undated (Box 21)
  - Bibliography, undated (Box 21)
  - Dynamics of Development, undated (Box 21)
  - Taxonomy, undated (Box 21)
  - Zoogeography, undated (Box 21)
  - Landauer research and notes, undated (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 22)
  - Genetics studies, undated (Box 22)
  - MIT Enterprise forum, undated (Box 22)
  - Landauer research, notes and drafts, undated (Box 23-24)
  - Seminar notices, undated (Box 25)
  - Cellular Biology course materials, undated (Box 25)
  - Embryology term paper, undated (Box 25)
  - Lecture notes and exams, undated (Box 25)
  - Developmental Genetics, undated (Box 25)
  - Printed materials and photographs, undated (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 26)
  - Data, undated (Box 26)
  - Financial records, undated, 1947 (Box 26)
  - Research Park, undated (Box 26)
  - Storrs EPT Station, undated (Box 26)
  - Center for Environmental Health, undated (Box 26)
  - CII Board, undated (Box 26)
  - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station, undated (Box 26)
  - US Memories, Inc., undated (Box 26)
  - Landauer research materials, undated (Box 27)
  - Connecticut Academy of Science and Engineering materials, undated (Box 27)